lotterywest.wa.gov.au 2009-11-11

# Legal — Lotterywest

## Copyright Information

Western Australian Government materials, including Internet pages, documents and on-line graphics, audio and video, are protected by copyright law. Copyright of Western Australian Government material resides with the State of Western Australia, apart from material or intellectual property that is held by Lotterywest in its own right. Apart from any fair dealing for the purposes of private study, research, criticism or review, as permitted under the provisions of the Copyright Act 1968, no part may be reproduced or re-used for any commercial purposes whatsoever without prior written permission of the State of Western Australia (or Lotterywest, where material is owned by Lotterywest).

## Disclaimer and Limit of Liability

This website may contain inaccurate, incomplete and outdated information and you should seek and rely upon your own independent enquiries, assessment and advice in relation to any advice or information contained in this website. 

Lotterywest's annual report provides detailed information inclusing a full list of organisations receiving grants during the financial year in question.

Lotterywest makes no warranties or representation about any content or information on this website, and to the extent permitted by law excludes (and where law does not permit an exclusion, limits to the extent permitted by law) all:

(a) warranties and representations about the currency, accuracy, suitability or reliability of any content or information on this website; and

(b) liability for any direct, indirect and consequential costs, losses, damages and expenses incurred in any way (including but not limited to that arising from negligence), connected with any use or access to this website or any reliance on information contained on this website.

## Changes

Lotterywest may make changes to this website and its content (including, without limitation, information, publications, prices and product offerings) at any time and without notice.

## Linking and Framing

This website may contain links to other websites and may on occasion display content or information from other websites within frames on this website. Lotterywest are not responsible for any such content or information and Lotterywest make no representation as to the accuracy or suitability of that content or information.

Lotterywest is committed to protecting your personal information. You are encouraged to read the information below, for further information including Lotterywest procedures or if you have any concerns or questions please contact Lotterywest on **(08) 9340 5200** (Monday-Friday during office hours 8.30am - 5.00pm) or email our Support team at [contact@lotterywest.wa.gov.au](mailto:contact@lotterywest.wa.gov.au).

## Personal information collection and Use

When you provide personal information, Lotterywest will inform you of how the information will be used. Lotterywest endeavours to protect the privacy of the information collected on the site [www.lotterywest.wa.gov.au](http://www.lotterywest.wa.gov.au/asp/index.asp) and associated Lotterywest owned domains. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement.

In some instances, in order to use some functions of this website, a user must first complete a registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information. This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information and unique identifiers, but encouraged so we can provide a more personalised experience on our site.

We use IP addresses to analyse trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

## 'Cookies'

We do not use 'cookies' in managing this website.

## Disclosure and sharing

The information collected from you is kept strictly confidential.

We may disclose the personal information, other information or data we collect from you for the purpose specified to you at the time of collection. If we wish to disclose this information, we will do so under your expressed approval and consent. We will not provide your e-mail address to third parties without your consent.

We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

## Links

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Lotterywest, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site [www.lotterywest.wa.gov.au](http://www.lotterywest.wa.gov.au/asp/index.asp), and associated, Lotterywest owned domains.

## Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information, and demographic information. Contact information will be used to notify the winners, award prizes and notify users of any further contests, promotions or products and services. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of the website.

## Security

This website takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or bank account number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just ‘surfing’.

While we use encryption software to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our help desk or customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information.

If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an e-mail to [contact@lotterywest.wa.gov.au](mailto:contact@lotterywest.wa.gov.au) or (08) 9340 5200 (Monday-Friday during normal office hours 8.30am - 5.00pm).

## Supplementation of Information

In order for this website to properly fulfil its obligation to our customers, it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from 3rd party sources. We combine information about the purchasing habits of users with similar information from other organisations such as the Australian Bureau of Statistics.

## Special Offers and Promotions

Established users will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see our choice and opt-out below.

## Site and Service Updates

We also send the user site and service announcement updates. Members are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via e-mail or phone.

## Correction/Updating Personal Information:

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes, or if a user no longer desires our service, we allow users to correct, update or remove that user’s personal data provided to us. This can be done by sending an e-mail to [contact@lotterywest.wa.gov.au](mailto:contact@lotterywest.wa.gov.au) with the details requiring changing or by calling customer enquiries on (08) 9340 5200 (Monday-Friday during normal office hours 8.30am - 5.00pm). Correcting and updating personal information will be carried out in accordance with Lotterywest procedures.

## Choice/Opt-out

Our users are given the opportunity to ‘opt-out’. Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials may opt-out of receiving these communications by following the unsubscribe process as indicated on mailing list messages. If the process does not automatically remove your subscription, then you can contact our Support team on [contact@lotterywest.wa.gov.au](mailto:contact@lotterywest.wa.gov.au) or call (08) 9340 5200 (Monday-Friday during normal office hours 8.30am - 5.00pm).

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether they should proceed.

## Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our website so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users and request permission from users by way of an e-mail. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
